Raymond, Eleanor. The Eleanor Raymond Collection: An Inventory.
Eleanor Raymond Collection.
- Series A / Project Files, A000
  - Project Files: Thompson House Alterations, / Date(s): 1961; : A6112
    Note: Project files related to Thompson House, 22 Larch Road, Cambridge, MA; extensive interior detailing.
    Content: Correspondence files contain yellow trace sketches.
  - Project Files: Peabody Dave's House, / Date(s): 1961; : A6113
    Note: Project files related to Peabody Dave's House, Powisset Street, Dover, MA.
  - Project Files: Richardson Project, / Date(s): 1961; : A6114
  - Project Files: Atkins Kitchen Alteration, / Date(s): 1962; : A6202
    Note: Project file related to Atkins House, Concord, MA.
  - Project Files: Ellis Garage, / Date(s): 1962; : A6204
    Note: Project file related to Ellis Garage, Groton, CT.
  - Project Files: White House Alterations, / Date(s): 1962; : A6205
    Note: Project files related to White House Alterations, 115 Juniper Road, Belmont, MA; large-scale details of interest.
  - Project Files: Rachel Warner Memorial Garden, / Date(s): 1962; : A6206
    Note: Project files related to Rachel Warner Memorial Garden, Ipswich School, Ipswich, MA.
  - Project Files: Woolsey Garden Projects, / Date(s): 1962; : A6208
    Note: Correspondence file contains 8.5" x 11" garden sketch.
  - Project Files: Garden Plan, / Date(s): 1962; : A6212
    Note: Correspondence file contains garden plan on yellow trace.
    Note: Contains mis-filed blueprint of project #6209; "Sketch for an absolutely flat roof."
  - Project Files: Schroeder House, / Date(s): 1962; : A6213
    Note: Project file related to Schroeder House, Wood's Hole, MA.
  - Project Files: Horowitz House Alterations, / Date(s): 1962; : A6214
    Note: Project file related to Horowitz House, Brockton, MA.
  - Project Files: Bowditch House Alterations, / Date(s): 1963; : A6301
    Note: Project file related to Bowditch House alterations; location not indicated.
  - Project Files: Jordan Interior Alterations, / Date(s): 1963; : A6302
    Note: Correspondence file contains 8.5" x 11" sketches.
  - Project Files: Ketchum House, / Date(s): 1963; : A6304
    Note: Project file related to Ketchum House, North Haven, ME.
  - Project Files: Weld House Alterations, / Date(s): 1963; : A6305
    Note: Correspondence file contains shop drawings.
  - Project Files: Atkins House Alterations, / Date(s): 1963; : A6306
    Note: Project files related to Atkins House Alterations, Pittsford, MA; alterations to a "1950's modern" house.
  - Project Files: Chase Kitchen Alterations, / Date(s): 1963; : A6307
    Note: Project file related to Chase House, Cambridge, MA.
  - Project Files: Thoron Interior Alterations, / Date(s): 1963; : A6308
    Note: Project file related to Thoron House; location not indicated.
  - Project Files: Stoneman Kitchen Alterations, / Date(s): 1963; : A6309
    Content: Correspondence file contains yellow trace and yellow paper sketches.
  - Project Files: Singer Townhouse Renovation, / Date(s): 1963; : A6310
    Note: Project files related to Singer Townhouse Renovation, 101 Chestnut Street, Boston, MA.
  - Project Files: Fuller Kitchen Alterations, / Date(s): 1963; : A6311
    Content: See project #4811 for mis-filed drawings.
  - Project Files: Irvine House, / Date(s): 1963-1964; : A6312
  - Project Files: Blewer House, / Date(s): 1964; : A6401
    Note: Project file related to Blewer House, Sugar Hill, NH.
  - Project Files: Bowditch House, / Date(s): 1964; : A6402
    Note: Project files related to Bowditch House, Camden, ME. Begins as house plans, but evolves into revisions to Deck Pre-Fabricated House plans.
    Content: Includes blueline prints of Deck House design for Bowditch, dated July, 1965 and red-lined.
  - Project Files: Winchester Kitchen Remodelling, / Date(s): 1964; : A6403
  - Project Files: Stevens House Remodeling, / Date(s): 1964; : A6404
    Content: Correspondence file contains map.
  - Project Files: Bishop Hunt Study, / Date(s): 1964; : A6405
    Content: Correspondence file contains sketches on paper.
  - Project Files: Bucknell House, / Date(s): 1964; : A6406
    Content: Correspondence file contains trace sketches.
    Content: Also contains sketches by owner.
  - Project Files: Nichols Project, / Date(s): 1964; : A6407
  - Project Files: Blewer Village House Alterations, / Date(s): 1964; : A6408
    Content: Correspondence file contains record sketches of existing house on yellow paper.
  - Project Files: Danforth House Alterations, / Date(s): 1964; : A6409
    Content: Correspondence file contains white trace sketch.
  - Project Files: Eliot House Alterations, / Date(s): 1964; : A6410
    Note: Project file related to Eliot House, West Manchester, MA.
  - Project Files: Taves House Addition, / Date(s): 1965; : A6501
    Note: Project file related to Taves House, Cambridge, MA.
  - Project Files: Gring House Addition, / Date(s): 1965; : A6502
    Note: Project files related to Gring House Addition, 15 Hubbard Park, Cambridge, MA.
    Content: Correspondence file contains shop drawings.
  - Project Files: Alexander Kitchen Remodeling, / Date(s): 1965; : A6503
    Note: Correspondence file contains record sketches of existing building and yellow trace sketches.
  - Project Files: Otis House Alterations, / Date(s): 1965; : A6505
    Content: Correspondence files contain measured sketches on 8.5" x 11" paper.
  - Project Files: Richardson House Alterations, / Date(s): 1965; : A6506
    Content: Correspondence file contains sketches on grid paper as well as abundant personal and job-related correspondence.
  - Project Files: Whitnack House Alterations, / Date(s): 1965; : A6507
    Note: Correspondence files contain sketches on large grid paper and on white 8.5" x 11".
  - Project Files: Wilkenson House Alterations, / Date(s): 1965; : A6508
  - Project Files: Storey House Addition, / Date(s): 1965; : A6509
    Note: Located on John Wise Road, Essex, MA.
  - Project Files: Markham House, / Date(s): 1965; : A6510
    Note: Project file related to Markham House, Belmont, MA.
  - Project Files: Reinert House Addition, / Date(s): 1965; : A6511
    Content: Correspondence file contains 8.5 x 11 sketch.
  - Project Files: Memorial Seat to Groton Hunt, / Date(s): 1965; : A6512
    Note: Project file related to design of memorial, Groton, MA.
  - Project Files: Eaton House Alterations, / Date(s): 1965; : A6513
    Note: Correspondence file contains measured sketches on 8.5" x 11" and large folded yellow trace sketches.
  - Project Files: Storey Well House, / Date(s): 1965; : A6514
    Note: Correspondence file contains yellow trace sketches.
    Note: Contains mis-filed drawings for Project #6101.
  - Project Files: Old South Church Projects, / Date(s): 1965-1966; : A6515
    Content: Correspondence file contains sketches on yellow trace.
  - Project Files: Hutchison House Alterations, / Date(s): 1966; : A6601
    Note: Project file related to Hutchison House, Ipswich, MA.
  - Project Files: Hart House Additions, / Date(s): 1966; : A6603
    Note: Project file related to Hart House Addition, Argilla Road, Ipswich, MA.
  - Project Files: Olmsted Superintendent's House Alteration, / Date(s): 1966; : A6604
    Note: Project files related to Olmsted Superintendent's House Alteration. Brookline site?
    Content: Correspondence file contains record sketches on 8.5" x 11" of existing building.
  - Project Files: Smith House Alterations, / Date(s): 1966; : A6605
    Content: Includes correspondence file.
  - Project Files: Brookings House, / Date(s): 1966; : A6606
    Note: Project file related to Brookings House, Rockport, MA.
  - Project Files: Preston House Alterations, / Date(s): 1966; : A6608
    Note: Project file related to Preston House, Squam Lake, NH.
  - Project Files: Wile Project, / Date(s): 1967; : A6609
    Note: Henry E. Wile a long-time associated friend of E. Raymond; builder on several of her projects.
  - Project Files: Alden House Alterations, / Date(s): 1967; : A6701
  - Project Files: Fitzgibbon Memorial, / Date(s): 1968; : A6702
    Note: Memorial cross designed and executed by Amelia Peabody in cooperation with E. Raymond for Fitzgibbon, a mutual friend.
    Content: Correspondence file only; no associated drawing file.
    Content: Correspondence file contains blackline print of A. Peabody sketch.
  - Project Files: Hubbard House Alterations, / Date(s): 1967; : A6703
    Note: Project file related to Hubbard House, Brookline, MA.
  - Project Files: Blewer House Alterations, / Date(s): 1968; : A6704
    Content: Includes one page of specifications.
  - Project Files: Mallery House Alterations, / Date(s): 1967; : A6706
    Note: Correspondence file contains record sketches on existing building on 8.5" x 11" yellow paper.
  - Project Files: Smith House Alterations, / Date(s): 1967; : A6708
    Content: Correspondence file contains 8.5" x 11" yellow paper sketch.
  - Project Files: Preston House Alterations, / Date(s): 1967; : A6709
  - Project Files: Smith House, / Date(s): 1973; : A6710
    Note: Project files related to Smith House, Biddeford, Maine; apparently "low cost" using Texture 111 siding.
    Content: Correspondence file contains sample from D/R at 48 Brattle Street as well as sketches on paper.
  - Project Files: Hunt Landscaping Project, / Date(s): 1969; : A6711
  - Project Files: Peabody exhibition, / Date(s): 1967; : A6712
  - Project Files: Burroughs Terrace, / Date(s): 1968; : A6801
    Note: Project file related to Burroughs House terrace, Hancock, NH.
  - Project Files: Counihan, / Date(s): --; : A6802
    Content: Empty file.
  - Project Files: Taves Garage Addition, / Date(s): 1968; : A6803
  - Project Files: Smith Townhouse Alterations, / Date(s): 1968; : A6804
    Note: Project file related to Smith Townhouse, Boston, MA.
  - Project Files: Bradley House Alterations, / Date(s): 1968; : A6806
    Content: Correspondence file contains shop drawings and sketch on 8.5" x 11" paper.
  - Project Files: Pereira House Alterations, / Date(s): 1968; : A6807
    Note: Project files related to Pereira House Alterations; concrete block; use of sliding glass replacement doors as windows.
  - Project Files: Chase House Alterations, / Date(s): 1968; : A6808
    Note: Project file related to Chase House, Manchester, MA.
  - Project Files: Danforth, / Date(s): --; : A6809
  - Project Files: Smith-Taylor House Alterations, / Date(s): 1968-1969; : A6810
    Content: Correspondence files contain Techbilt drawings and brochure.
  - Project Files: Fulton Project, / Date(s): 1968; : A6811
  - Project Files: Jordan House Alterations, / Date(s): 1968; : A6812
    Content: Correspondence file contains measured sketches.
  - Project Files: Peabody Deck House, / Date(s): 1968; : A6813
    Content: Includes Deck House plans.
  - Project Files: Phillips House Additions, / Date(s): 1970; : A6901
  - Project Files: Sargent House Additions, / Date(s): 1969; : A6902
    Note: Project file related to Sargent House, Manchester, MA.
  - Project Files: von Mertens House, / Date(s): 1970; : A6903
    Note: Project files related to von Mertens House, 200 Lexington Avenue, Weston, MA.
  - Project Files: Cabot Project, / Date(s): 1969; : A6904
  - Project Files: Perkins House Interiors, / Date(s): 1970; : A7001
    Content: Correspondence file contains blackline prints, shop drawings and site trace sketches.
  - Project Files: Preston House Alterations, / Date(s): 1970; : A7002
  - Project Files: Brookings Kitchen Remodeling, / Date(s): 1970; : A7003
    Content: Correpondence file contains sketches.
  - Project Files: Strock House Alterations, / Date(s): 1970; : A7004
    Content: Correspondence file contains small sketches.
  - Project Files: Baxter-Ward Antique Shop, / Date(s): 1970; : A7005
    Content: Correspondence file contains measured sketches on 8.5" x 11" paper, sketches on yellow trace and on grid paper.
  - Project Files: Grote, / Date(s): 1970; : A7006
  - Project Files: Baxter-Ward Speculative Housing, / Date(s): 1970; : A7007
    Content: Correspondence file contains record sketches of existing building and 8.5" x 11" sketches.
  - Project Files: Dickerson House Alterations, / Date(s): 1970; : A7008
    Content: Correspondence file contains full set of Techbilt blueprints and a drawing on vellum.
  - Project Files: Story Project, / Date(s): 1970; : A7009
  - Project Files: Simon Project, / Date(s): 1970; : A7010
    Content: Correspondence file contains white trace and yellow paper sketches.
  - Project Files: Brown House Interiors, / Date(s): 1970; : A7011
    Content: Correspondence file contains sketches on yellow trace and yellow paper.
  - Project Files: Whitnack Project, / Date(s): 1970; : A7012
    Content: Correspondence file contains small sketches on yellow paper.
  - Project Files: Perkins House Alterations, / Date(s): 1972; : A7101
    Content: Correspondence file contains client comments and drawings.
  - Project Files: Blewer House Addition, / Date(s): 1971; : A7102
    Content: Correspondence file contains site sketch on yellow trace.
  - Project Files: Munn House Addition, / Date(s): 1971; : A7103
    Content: Correspondence file contains sketches; some on white trace.
  - Project Files: Callahan House Alterations, / Date(s): 1971; : A7104
    Note: Project file related to Callahan House, East Brewster, MA.
  - Project Files: Norstad Project, / Date(s): 1972; : A7201
  - Project Files: Blewer Studio, / Date(s): --; : A7202
    Content: Correspondence file contains white trace sketches.
    Content: Empty drawing file.
  - Project Files: Raymond House, / Date(s): 1972; : A7203
    Content: Empty drawing and correspondence files.
  - Project Files: Stevens, / Date(s): --; : A7204
  - Project Files: Taplin Kitchen Remodeling, / Date(s): 1972; : A7205
    Note: Project file related to Taplin House, Dublin, NH.
  - Project Files: Peabody "Westville Sporthaus", / Date(s): 1972; : A7206
    Note: Project files related to Peabody "Westville Sporthaus", Powisset Street, Dover, MA. Prototype for pre-built house to be sold by Westville.
    Content: Correspondence files contain Westville specifications, Westville brochure, Westville plans.
  - Project Files: PESP - Mr. Harrold, / Date(s): 1972; : A7207
    Content: Correspondence files contain trace sketches.
    Content: Correspondence file contains copy of gardening book, Year-round Gardening in Your Own Greenhouse.
  - Project Files: Peabody Pool, / Date(s): 1972; : A7208
    Content: Correspondence file contains sketches and shop drawings.
  - Project Files: Brown House Alterations, / Date(s): 1972; : A7209
    Note: Project file related to Brown House, Duxbury, MA.
  - Project Files: Leach, / Date(s): --; : A7301
    Note: Former house of Eleanor Raymond's sister, Rachel, built for her by Eleanor in 1930. Correspondence file contains notes about work to be done there by new owner, Dr. Leon Leach. 105 Juniper Road, Belmont, MA.
  - Project Files: Williams House Alterations, / Date(s): 1973; : A7302
    Content: Correspondence file contains yellow trace sketches and record sketches of existing building on grid paper.
    Content: Empty drawing file. See project #7308 for mis-filed drawings (sketches and measured drawings).
  - Project Files: Ellis House, / Date(s): 1973; : A7303
    Note: Project file related to Ellis House, Inverness, FLA.
  - Project Files: Wolfe House Alteration Projects, / Date(s): 1973; : A7304
    Content: Correspondence file contains yellow trace sketch, sketches on paper and measured record sketches of existing building on grid paper.
  - Project Files: McFarland Project, / Date(s): 1973; : A7305
    Content: Correspondence file contains sketches on trace and grid paper.
  - Project Files: Spencer House Alterations, / Date(s): 1973; : A7306
    Content: Correspondence file contains yellow trace sketches and measured record sketches of existing building on grid paper.
  - Project Files: Kinkade House Alterations, / Date(s): 1973; : A7307
  - Project Files: Union Pacific Station Project, / Date(s): 1973; : A7308
    Content: Correspondence file contains blackline print of sketch on grid paper.
  - Project Files: Rose Project, / Date(s): 1973; : A7309
    Content: Correspondence file contains sketch on paper.
  - Project Files: Hunt House Project, / Date(s): 1974; : A7401
  - Project Files: Brookings Project, / Date(s): 1974; : A7402
    Note: Empty correspondence file and no associated drawing file.
  - Project Files: Gilfillan House Alterations, / Date(s): 1974; : A7403
    Content: Correspondence file contains photocopied 8.5" x 11" sketches.
  - Project Files: Beckman Pool Project, / Date(s): 1975; : A7501
    Content: Correspondence files contain measured record sketch of existing building as well as client's sketch.
  - Project Files: Ward House Alterations, / Date(s): 1975; : A7502
  - Project Files: Osgood House Alterations, / Date(s): 1975; : A7503
    Content: Correspondence file contains measured record sketches of existing building on 8.5" x 11".
- Series B / Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice, B000
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Farnsworth House, / Date(s): --; : B001
    Note: This may be project #353.
    Content: Box #1 contains unidentified journal and Architectural Forum (November 1943) articles.
    Published in: Published in Architectural Forum, November 1943, 82-83. Published in (unidentified journal), "House Once Removed", by Ethel B. Power, 63.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Rachel Raymond House, / Date(s): --; : B002
    Note: Box #1 contains House Beautiful (October 1932) and Architectural Forum Master Detail Series articles.
    Published in: Published in House Beautiful, October 1932, 200-207 & 263-264. Architectural Forum, Master Detail Series, 413-418.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Ellis House, / Date(s): --; : B003
    Content: Box #1 contains Architectural Record (October 1934), House Beautiful (March 1932) and House Beautiful (April 1932) articles.
    Published in: Published in House Beautiful, April 1932, 280-285 & 311-312. House Beautiful, March 1932, 170-178. Architectural Record October 1934, 298.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: 112 Charles Street, / Date(s): --; : B004
    Content: Box #1 contains Architectural Record (no date), House Beautiful (November 1924, November 1926 and October 1923) articles.
    Published in: Published in House Beautiful, November 1926, 554 & 557-559 & 612-?. House Beautiful, October 1923, 349-350. House Beautiful, November 1926, 573-576. Architectural Record (date?), 573-579. House Beautiful, November 1924, 462-468 & 514-516.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Safford House, / Date(s): --; : B005
    Content: Box #1 contains Architectural Record (November 1932) article.
    Published in: Published in Architectural Record, November 1932, 316-318.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Raymond Office, / Date(s): --; : B006
    Content: Box #1 contains Architectural Record article.
    Published in: Published in Architectural Record, May 1937, 42.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Smith House, / Date(s): --; : B007
    Content: Box #1 contains House Beautiful (September 1928 and October 1928) articles.
    Published in: Published in House Beautiful, September 1928, 238 & 241-245 & 310-312. House Beautiful, October 1928, 383-387.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Cleaves House, / Date(s): --; : B008
    Content: Box #1 contains House Beautiful (March 1922 and November 1922) articles.
    Published in: Published in House Beautiful, March 1922, 218. House Beautiful, November 1922, 420-423 & 468-?
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Jackson House, / Date(s): --; : B009
    Content: Box #1 contains House Beautiful (January 1927) article.
    Published in: Published in House Beautiful, January 1927, 24 & 58-59.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Lennihan House, / Date(s): --; : B010
    Content: Box #1 contains House Beautiful (April 1928 & May 1928) articles.
    Published in: Published in House Beautiful, April 1928, 11. House Beautiful, May 1928, 437-438.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Mitchell Studio, / Date(s): --; : B011
    Content: Box #1 contains House Beautiful (September 1993and July 1932) articles.
    Published in: Box #1 contains House Beautiful (September 1933 and July 1932) articles.
    Published in: Published in House Beautiful, September 1933, 104C-E & 104L. House Beautiful, July 1932, 25.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Early Domestic Architecture of Pennsylvania, / Date(s): 1973; : B012
    Note: One copy of E. Raymond's Early Domestic Architecture of Pennsylvania, 1973 edition. Introductions by E. Raymond and John Milner, AIA. Includes many photographs and measured drawings.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Early Domestic Architecture of Pennsylvania, / Date(s): 1931; : B013
    Note: Ethel Power's signed copy of Eleanor Raymond's 1931 publication of Early Domestic Architecture of Pennsylvania. This is a large-format book.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: The Smaller American House, / Date(s): 1927; : B014
    Note: Eleanor Raymond's signed copy of her friend Ethel Power's book The Smaller American House.
    Content: Box #2 contains this book.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Publicity, / Date(s): 1946; : B015
    Content: Box #1 contains publicity folder with correspondence from the Architectural League of New York, Institute of Contemporary Art in Boston and articles on women in architecture.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Dwellings, / Date(s): 1946; : B016
    Content: Box #1 contains dwellings folder with article by Frost, articles on and correspondence from Massachusetts Women's Suffrage Organization.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Doris Cole Manuscript, / Date(s): --; : B017
    Note: Manuscript of Doris Cole's book on Eleanor Raymond.
    Content: Box #2 contains this manuscript in a blue binder.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Doris Cole Manuscript, / Date(s): --; : B018
    Note: Editor's copy of Doris Cole manuscript for book on Eleanor Raymond.
    Content: Box #1 contains this manuscript.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Specifications Workbook, / Date(s): --; : B019
    Note: 3-ring binder showing work to be described in various specification sections and AIA Documents dating from the 1950's and before.
    Content: Box #2 contains this notebook.
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Job Address, Client and List, / Date(s): --; : B020
    Note: 3-ring binder containing lists of clients, locations, etc., 6" x 9".
  - Published and Unpublished Materials / Professional Practice: Building Statistics, / Date(s): --; : B021
    Note: 3-ring binder with typed pages showing construction costs / building statistics for each job; 8.5" x 11". Information includes: client, builder, costs and building description.
- Series C / Photos, Other Graphic Material and Memorabilia / Professional Practice, / Date(s): 1946; C000
  - Photos, Other Graphic Material and Memorabilia / Professional Practice: Photographs, / Date(s): 1946; : C001
    Content: Box #1 contains file folder of unsorted personal and professional photographs.
  - Photos, Other Graphic Material and Memorabilia / Professional Practice: Photo Mussell Point House, / Date(s): --; : C002